To me, the interesting bit here is to
think about them stepping into this
complexity that all of these AI labs
will have now, which is where is it that
I want to be a platform that people
build on and I want them to be able to
trust that they can build on me and I'm
not going to go and try and compete with
them directly after and start limiting
their access etc. And where is it that
they actually want to capitalize on the
solutions and I think in the software
engineering space more and more appetite
from these labs to be that solution.
Anthropic specifically is an interesting
spot on they have a lot of fans in the
AI dev space that are building on top of
it and so I I think if you're them you
want to be very sensitive.
You're listening to the AI native dev
brought to you by Tesla.
[Music]
Hello and welcome to uh another monthly
roundup of the AI Native Dev. My name is
Simon. Joining me once again, Kai Pani.
Hey Simon, it's fun to do another.
Absolutely. And and this time around
we're going to take a look at what's
been happening in the wonderful month of
February and we had some amazing news.
We had some wonderful sessions as
normally on the podcast. Guy, another
month goes by, another model or more
models in this case. like 17 of them or
maybe a little bit less. Yeah. But
definitely was a big news day or news
month with with both sort of GP45 and
Sonnet 37 and and actually like earlier
in the month rock 3 in the process.
Yeah. Like a lot of a lot of numbers and
a lot of funky names. It is interesting
and and we'll go through those. I think
the two that people are most drawn to
here GPT45 and set 37. We'll go through
those. That sounds like you're biased a
little bit affected by the liberal
media. my training data has been
slightly poisoned. So yeah, I'm I'm
leaning towards them, too. As long as
you don't say that and think negative
about the losses are okay. Yeah,
absolutely. So let's go ahead and talk.
Actually, no. First of all, before we
deep dive into the models, do you feel
like that there seems to be like this
snowball effect where very often one
vendor, one model vendor releases an
update and all of a sudden we see
another one and another one and it's
weird. It's like one of those car races
where everyone's nudging in front every
five minutes. Do you feel like there is
huge outside pressure from businesses,
investors, marketing teams for for
companies to release because others are
equally released in that month or week?
Very convenient. Without a doubt, there
is like massive pressure of it. Part of
it is just dominating the news cycle.
So, it's just like this thing is the
sort of whole world is really hitting
mainstream media and everybody talks
about it. And so I think you don't want
to let any other player if you're one of
these big players dominate the news for
any window of time. So you want to
pierce in and and break it out. And I
think that's true for all of them. But I
also think that there is like just the
pace of experimentations and trials and
all that is very high. And so there is
also an element of literally amidst
users uh when you kind of get people to
that are excited to try a new thing. If
you let that sort of sit for longer
those users might get a little bit set
in their ways. Yeah. And so it's
interesting there is there's an open
question about how much would people
actually end up sticking to one model
over time. Like right now they feel very
interchangeable. You can switch from
whatever your claw chat to your opening
eye chat and we'll talk about that a bit
more. But I guess the some view
especially like the big investors like
in the latest anthropic round that also
happened just now. They believe that
there there are some tracks that are
being set. are some patterns and that
may be similar to what happened in the
cloud which is the sort of the initial
impression is like fine I didn't I can
run it on whatever EC2 or whatever other
sort of clouds equivalent but in
practice over time as the fine details
have expanded moving clouds is actually
not at all easy that maybe this will
happen as well in net labs I don't think
we're seeing it now so for now I think
it's more like new cycle domination and
uh getting users yeah yeah very
interesting let's dig down into a couple
of them we'll start with GPT45 which I
think was released released first. Was
that right? Seems a long time. Yeah. No,
but I think Sonic 37 actually came out
first. So, the reaction was 45.
Interesting. So, we'll start with we'll
start with the most recent going
backwards. Let's put it that way. So,
DBT4 recency bias here. Like I'm just
detecting a lot of bias. A lot of bias.
One of the interesting things and this
came out in a lot of the OpenAI
marketing was this mention of it being
having higher EQ than previous models,
the the the 45 release. And some of the
examples there some someone prompting
saying I'm going through a tough time
after failing a test. And you look at 40
which tries to solve the problem but 45
is actually far more compassionate and
trying to understand what the what the
user really actually wants. Is it do
they just want to chat about it? They
want to know someone's there. And it's a
far more dare I say claudlike personable
response. That's an interesting one. And
I feel like people I don't know I'm I'm
going to give maybe my personal bias
now, but people I find connect with
Claude because it is more human than
some of the other GPTs. This is a very
interesting move to have this more
personal. I think it's an interesting
choice. There's a little bit of an
acknowledgement that it's not just about
your sort of benchmark numbers and how
you're handling that, but also about
just sentiment for it. And so I think I
I think that is interesting like it's
been identified as a strength of claude
and OpenAI is trying to counter that on
it. I think there's also an element of
just styles that people prefer, right?
There's the whole kind of what is women
are from Venus, men are from Mars, 40 is
from Mars and five is from Venus. But
yeah, and it is quite noticeable.
There's been some interesting and I
think valid push back that you might not
really want a model that is one style
and a model that is of another, but
rather to be able to express a little
bit more of what type of conversation do
you want at the moment. And I think
actually in clog that you see in the
drop downs what style do you prefer? Do
you want a more formal conversation? Do
you want more of a personal? And
defaults to personal. But but it's
interesting. It's I think especially
interesting that there isn't again a
benchmark that you can win on this EQ.
So it'll basically be judged by the
population. I I don't think like maybe
people are trying but I don't think you
can really measure how human almost like
counterintuitive right like how human
are you in your in your responses. Yeah.
It's interesting like you say I'm really
trying to stop myself saying Grock is
from Uranus but I I I feel like I can't
I feel like I can't just leave that
sitting there. So I'll I'll finish with
that. But I think some of the open AI
tests that have that they've done
themselves very interesting as well.
They talk about essentially whether
humans prefer the responses from 45
versus 40 and on the and big caveat this
is the open AI tests everyday queries.
uh 57% of people prefer the 45 versus
40. Uh 63% of professional queries and
56% of creative intelligence. So there
is data that kind from open AI that says
people do lean towards those although I
know there are some others I think you
were mentioning you saw something on
Twitter. There was surveys that counter
that a little bit. I think in general
say we really have to this is such a
massive sort of domain of actions and
preferences and so much sort of room for
subjective analysis uh that I think it's
a little bit hard to really take any
data that comes out of these labs.
3 published a bunch of numbers that were
cast in doubt. Now these ones from I
don't think it's even like a wrongdoing
by them. Like clearly they will take a a
royal you wouldn't publish the stats
that you have that are negative about
you. I think Karpathy put out a survey
on Twitter where he did some blind
testing put some A and B responses that
alternated between four and four five
responses expecting everybody to then
prefer the four or five responses.
Actually the survey ended up favoring
40. Yeah. And and I think that's a
little bit underwhelming. I think it's
important to put this a little bit in
context of this sort of four five
release right so 4.5 is the first kind
of increment of the number right since 4
got released two years ago or like March
of 23 and so I think the expectation
that people kind of have for this model
the expectations they have is are really
quite substantial right the it's
estimated to be to have been sort of 10
times more expensive to train it is
between 15 and 30 times more expensive
in terms of tokens depending on your
input and output and and so I think you
come into it and you expect something
that would blow you away. So I would say
that even the open AI stats that sort of
say people slightly favor four or five
don't quite match the expectations.
People think more like we're expecting
maybe something that's more like three
to four like GP3 to GPT4. They only
incremented half a number. Maybe there's
a a statement in that. So unlike the
reasoning models that feel like they
really leveled up what the LLMs can do,
45 was a little underwhelming. Unless
I'm reading those numbers, right,
there's only a slight leaning in
sentiment towards the 45 even with the
open AI numbers. And in the blind
testing, it was even on the other side
of it. You know, Karpatio was wondering
about whether the connoisseurs like the
people I forget he had a slightly more
humble kind of term for it for uh people
with fine taste for LLM's output of it
might prefer the 45 as he does. So maybe
there's element of that, but again I
just I I find it's not about whether
people prefer four five. Let's say 45
would consistently get slightly better
than average preference. I guess coming
in you just say, "Hey, they're going to
release this thing. It's going to be
this sort of big price differential and
all that." I would expect it to be kind
of a landslide, right? Like to win by a
mile and and it's not doing that. And
and OpenAI interestingly do also share
some accuracy figures where they show on
their simple QA accuracy tests an
improvement. It's a reasonable
improvement. You're looking at I don't
know what's this 10 20% on top of 40 and
01. Uh a significant maybe what's that
40 45% increase over 03 mini.
Hallucinations are down as well across
the other three models 401 and 03 mini.
So they are showing some kind of stats
that I would more believe in the sense
of if you look at them it's actually
tests that are run across multiple right
because people would replicate those. So
it doesn't really serve them to uh to
publish anything that would therefore
thereafter be debunked. Yeah. Now rumor
has it. Rumor has it guy Tesla building
a product as well. It's not a model of
course. So just to clarify after talking
about models, it's not a model but we
use other models in our uh code
generation and and and throughout the
development workflow. So we've done
we've built evals of our own and we've
tested the various new models that have
come out as every eval team I'm sure on
red alert on a week of multiple models
coming out. Everybody's very curious
like it's it's work but I think people
are excited. Yeah, absolutely. It
reminds me of when a security
vulnerability comes out and everyone's
all hands on deck. It reminds me of that
when an ev when a new model comes out,
all eval teams and development teams are
are hard at work trying to test and I'm
sure see what it can do. Yeah. Yeah.
Product teams are like I think there's a
little bit more excitement when you get
that kind of vulnerability of it. But so
yeah, we tested 4.5 for us. The results
were actually uh not exciting at all. So
on the codeg genen side and and actually
it's not just codegen because we talk
about creating specifications and
understanding them and such but a lot of
it is around systems understanding. it
actually did worse than 40 and not by a
small amount. Now I want to caveat that
a little bit that I do think every model
has there's a level of just like hey
throw the previous model's prompts and
processes at it and see uh how it fares
and then there's like levels of
optimization and we have seen cases in
which when you optimize you actually
surpass what you can do with the what
you've optimized for before but the gap
is not small so the numbers are not
accurate enough to really share precise
numbers here we're still evaluating them
but it it really is like substantially
below 40 and I think it it comes down a
little bit also like this comment on
hallucinations. What we've seen over
over the past sort of six months is that
even within the same model within 40
releases of it, they're not always
progressing on a straight line. And so
some of them might come more creative,
some of them might become more whatever
analytical. Uh and so we've even seen
regressions within the same model over
time in terms of their specific code
gen. And working with OpenAI, it's
actually it's it's legit, right? It is
different capabilities in different
areas of the model. I think what's a
little bit odd here is like we're trying
to do something that is more analytical
and and in that it did not fair as well
and that that should be if they're
highlighting the uh reduced
hallucinations and things like that
those like it should be better over
there but it does maybe align with their
statement on the emphasis on EQ and and
human interactions which might not serve
for our purposes might not be as as
important and so I think what we're
learning like so so I would say high
level jur is still out we need to try it
out it's first models maybe there would
be big improvements on it. It'll be
interesting to see the reasoning models
that are built on top of 45 or top of
40. So I think there's a lot to still
see but arrival hasn't blown us away
like it has actually been a bit of a
setback and I think it's hard right now
to say yeah I will pay like on order of
magnitude more for for switching to it
and that's our experience but also
generally like I' I've really have yet
to see someone really swear by it. So,
we'll see. Not not hasn't arrived with
with a big wave of success. Yeah. And
actually, let's switch across now to
Sonet 35. You talked a little bit about
reason. I keep doing that. It's been 35
so long. It's been 35 for so long. I
automatically default to that. Sonet 37.
You mentioned reasoning. One of the big
things that dropped in Sonet 37, of
course, was dynamic reasoning. It's the
first hybrid model. Re first hybrid
reasoning model on the market, as they
state as a combined model. It does.
Yeah. step-by-step style thinking
similar to Deepseek, right? The way Deep
Seek very verbosely stated what it was
doing. What are your thoughts on first
of all the denim reasoning aspect and
yeah secondly I guess comparisons to
other models to to the AI models? I
think there's a few things to note for
it. So first of all exciting to see the
reasoning models from anthropic. I think
it's the first reasoning model thinking
model and I think that has definitely
pioneered by OpenAI but it's now being
accepted as the right model. Maybe I
should say three things. one is indeed
they've chosen to be open with its
thinking like deepseek. It doesn't
ramble on and on as much as R1 like
Deepseek. Yeah, it's chatty. You were
worried about your tokens when you saw
it chatting back. It really takes a
while to make up its mind which is by
the way fascinating especially when ask
when you see how it thinks about what it
should answer to appease the human.
There's a level of trust in that though
when you see that you believe it's doing
the right thing and you feel and it's
charming for a moment and then just gets
in the way and and and you can collapse
it. I think there new versions actually
now are allow you to hide that a bit
more. So it seems like have actually
toned that down a bit more but it is
more open than open AI and I think maybe
to an extent OpenAI's decision to hide
the the reasoning logic didn't work
maybe as much as they might have planned
in the sense of delaying others from
creating reasoning models just based on
the pace of others releasing them. Yes,
but definitely it's a different choice
that's more transparent and you're right
a bit more sort of trust building and
just interesting like we do see that
when we look at the reasoning logic for
instance it guides us as to uh as to
where is it that we might have gotten a
prompt correct or or not. Yeah. So I
think that's interesting that's maybe a
bit more on the sort of aesthetics or
some choices of it. I think the the
second aspect of it is indeed this
dynamic reasoning that's actually uh
novel. It's been mentioned by OpenAI.
It's been mentioned by Google before. or
so I don't think it's a new concept but
I think it's the first one that actually
provides it I'm not entirely sure but
the Gemini one and what it means is you
can have the model tell the model how
hard to think and that's a difference
between open AAI's world in which you
choose whether to go to a non-thinking
or a fast thinking model like 40 or 45
or do you go to to to these thinking
models one and 03 03 mini and you have
them produce and and think deeply here
they're saying like hey we don't want
you to switch models. It is the same
model and you just want to say how many
cycles, how many kind of iterations or
digestion you have around it. I don't
exactly know the sort of the math behind
the scenes. But uh I think it makes more
sense from a user perspective, right? I
don't want to choose does this require
thought or not. I don't want the binary
level of think a little bit or or think
a ton and just max them in. So I think
it's really interesting and I think
people will play with it. I do think
that the uh hope is that it would figure
it out itself. If I ask you how much uh
3.3 3 plus 3 is then or what's the
latest version of us on it on it. I'll
give you an answer. Yes. Don't put me on
the spot. I'll give you an answer. You
you might I might expect you to not
think very hard about this, right?
Versus I I'd give you a multiplications
of some sort of seven-digit numbers. I
might expect you to pen a paper and
start writing. And so I think there
might be uh another layer coming that
decides how much to think. Yeah, I think
that's pretty interesting. Like I I
guess I relate to that from a product
sensibility perspective. I don't have a
strong opinion around its implications
of the model, right? There's a you can
you can imagine how it really should be
a very different model, one that is just
like snappy and gives you the result
versus one that is a a deep thinker and
and I think talking about it from the
product point of view, one of the first
certainly one of the first I saw react
to it was bolt new. And of course I I'm
a massive fan of bolt. I must admit,
I've used Bolt new numerous times now
and creating like fun prototypes as a
Java backend developer. Yes, hands up.
I'm happy and proud to admit it. I'm
useless at front end development. So,
Bolt that will actually do that for me.
And I'm not a good design person either.
I don't know why you hired me, guy. I'm
not a good design person. Not a good
sort of opening up all these other fats
on it, but I think you're doing a good
job. So, so yeah, from my point of view,
Bulk just does it fills in the gap. We
talked about it filling in the gaps. It
fills in my gaps in terms of my the
areas that I don't necessarily uh find
natural to to to build. But one of the
interesting things is they introduced
dynamic reasoning as a toggle. It's a
beta for them. They introduced that into
their product and and it allows them
based on the request that a user sends,
does it need to think deeply or not? And
to your point, if I'm changing a color
of something or if I'm doing something
where it just needs to effectively do
something similar that I could do in the
code just as a copy replace or
something, but I don't want to have to
dig in the code, it can just do that
very quickly. But if I'm, you know,
asking it for a major architectural
reformatting or architectural decision,
yes, it needs to think more deeply. So
it's really interesting to add that and
for it to be able to say yes. And I
think that makes a lot of sense and it's
I think a part of the claw bet is that
people want to be able to control which
actions require that which again open
also makes possible by basically making
a call to one model to and the other. Uh
I think what's interesting to sort of
see is how people relate to the how much
uh do you want to think. It's easy to
say here you don't need to think like
here just give me a quick answer and
here think deeply before you answer uh
when is it that I would want you to say
think 40% hard right or think 60% hard
and so I
think it depends on what the sort of the
reality of the output is but that's no
pun intended but a little bit harder to
reason about and say what what is what
are the cases in which you want to think
hard but not hardest yes uh about and
how where is it that you're willing to
take a latency hit but not complete
latency hit. Yeah, you do see a little
bit more uh in claude despite all that
sensibilities you do see that at least
at the API level they have maybe a bit
more of an enterprise use case bias and
so there's a lot more flexibility that
with how they've approached MCP versus
the more sort of uh simplified tool use
that that that OpenAI touts. So there's
again maybe a little bit of that sort of
different flavors, different tracks that
different models are are choosing. I do
think there's a third bit that's
interesting around around philanthropic
and the reasoning release which is first
of all there is a difference I want to
note that there is a difference between
what they do in the API and the more
simplicity that they have in the user
product. So when you use claude you do
just have a binary so more similar 03
and 01. So I think the the third thing
to say about about Enthropic is is there
a sort of recent choice also to launch
uh cloud code and I think in code is
once again a little bit of that sort of
flexibility sensibilities unlike maybe
some of the others they have chosen to
release more CLIesque type tool for code
generation and I find that to be
interesting kind of maybe the other bit
about the less discussed aspect of sort
of the cloud release with 37 I'm sure it
builds on the capabilities within but I
think you're seeing maybe two things
inction here. One is of course they're
sort of leaning into an application type
capability and we've seen that with a
chat product of it but I think it's the
first we're seeing from anthropic to try
and offer something that's a bit more
sort of complete use case. Yes. And the
other is is maybe just I don't know if
you're seeing it but a thought that
comes up is how do they relate that to
people that are building on top of them
like cursor like bolt new uh and to me
the interesting bit here is to think
about uh them stepping into this
complexity that all of these AI labs
will have now uh which is uh where is it
that I want to be a platform that people
build on and I want them to be able to
trust that they can build on me and I'm
not going to go and try and compete with
them directly after and start limiting
their access etc. and where is it that
they actually want to capitalize on the
solutions and I think in the software
engineering space more and more appetite
from these labs to be that solution
specifically is an interesting spot on
they have a lot of fans in the AI dev
space that are building on top of it and
so I I think if you're them you want to
be very sensitive to what are the
statements you're making around when
should you use anthropic solutions
directly yeah and I think you're spot on
there with the CLI by ultimately being
an extensibility point for for others to
build upon and and yeah it's a cuz if
you think about what they have done in
the past where you are able to cla
artifacts and things like that where
you're able to actually build a little
react app and you can stand the front
end up and that that's the closest we've
got to them building something
specifically for developer interactions
to to to to build with claude code is is
that bigger step where it's a separate
release and I think it's in beta only
right now that yeah it's calling out for
people to build on top of it because I
don't think someone going in a developer
going in wants to use a CLI. I think ADA
was in the early days I say early days
like it was like Yeah. And I think it's
still around Ador but definitely was
innovating at the time. Yeah. Yeah. And
no one's really followed that path. So I
think Claude is looking at this not as a
full UI for for a developer to use, but
more for builders and and tinkerers to
to it's a good it's a good theory, but I
think it's a tricky balance and I've
actually just alluding to a great
episode we had this month with a guest
which is I did actually discuss this
very topic with Mati from 11 Labs. Yeah.
So let's jump over to the part to the
podcast. There are a few episodes that
we had this month. Do you know do you
remember when we were at state of open
con way back when I think it was 19 1990
something I can't remember it feels like
a long time a few weeks ago it feels
like a long time ago yeah early early
February we did an ask me anything live
from the state of open con um wonderful
open source uh conference and yeah had
some great questions great discussions
with a full panel do you know what guy I
think it feels so long ago and so much
has happened I don't I think we've
covered that we actually had a a session
just before with the January monthly
where we talked about it in the news as
well. I don't think I think we've
covered enough deepseek too much to do
to do that. We'll talk about it again
when hugging face eventually launches.
It's whatever sort of US US core a good
panel worth doing if you still have
questions about deepseek I think we
covered quite a lot of topics the legal
side of it the just like many aspects of
DC actually I lied guy I'm going to ask
one question about it yeah I'm I'm going
to go just because we said that do you
think they will be able to either build
or we talk about how deepseat distilled
from other models with things like
dynamic reasoning can you distill
dynamic reasoning from a model or do you
feel like you actually have to have um
almost like dynamic reasoning plug-in
kind of things. It's a it's a tricky
one, right? I think they're all if
distillable is is a word, but I think
basically the sort of the recent history
has shown that it's all mimickable on
it. Fundamentally, as I understand it,
if you were to simplify, you would say
fundamentally what you need is you need
data. So you need the ability to say hey
if I if I you know pass this input these
sets of inputs tokens or whatever kind
of they may hold I expect this type of
response or I can evaluate this response
and so as long as you are able to
extract that out of uh others to be able
to create the synthetic data then you're
able to train your system. I'm sure
there's also algorithmic aspects of of
how to interpret that and all that.
there's more complexity to it, but at
the core of it, if you have access to
the model and you can see how it
responds, you can generate more and more
data that helps you mimic that behavior.
And so I do think dynamic reasoning is
is a setting like if it becomes useful
and if there are I don't know maybe the
world doesn't like temperature, right?
But is it's still a bit of a voodoo
parameter. People find value in it. They
but but do you really know the
difference between 0.6 and 0.5? And
probably not that much. So maybe the
there's some three or four like voodoo
dynamic reasoning kind of levels that
people get used to. Then people will
probably distill that and and and and
copy it over. So yeah, I do think
actually if anything both 45 and 37 both
demonstrate the continued kind of a
parade indeed of of just everybody
moving together. uh I have not seen like
know what have we just discussed right
in four five the conversation is about
open AI mimicking claude with it sort of
EQ and sensibilities and in claude and
and anthropics models we talk about them
basically mimicking things that that
OpenAI has done around reasoning and
around maybe a little bit of like the
equivalent to their canvas with the code
creation and so there are subtle
differences around how they build it but
fundamentally I think they're all
copying one another and again Grock has
done that and I think there are bigger
changes like you see rock and deepseeek
here we are talking about this again uh
which are polar opposites in terms of
how you train and the underlying uh
models and so you have deepseeek working
on whatever low-level and not utilize
like squeezing the most out of old
hardware versus grock you know like just
uh xi they're throwing tons and tons of
money to be able to get the latest
Nvidias but somehow they both end up
producing things that are comparable
similarly I think anthropic has made a
big bet on using Amazon's GPUs and so
there sort of implementation choices
I've to really see something that feels
like a sustainable difference between
them. Yeah. Yeah. So, let's go into
let's jump into the next two. But first,
I want to do a quick shout out for
people who are interested in the kind of
like the model comparisons. I recorded
an amazing session with Macy Baker who
talked about prompt engineering on a
previous podcast. She's a community
engineer at Tessle. It was so much fun
talking about how she created uh a
couple of games, one as a as the
werewolves game, one as a split steel
kind of game, and we paired models
against each other and it was hilarious.
If you want to talk about EQ, just wait
till you hear what happens with Llama
and also with with Deep Seekers. Also,
some other news from the AI native dev,
which is that do you remember the
conference that we ran last last year in
November, AI native dev? It was amazing.
We actually decided a year is too long
to wait for another one. Things move so
fast. We have a 2025 spring edition of
the AI8 confused with a Java spring of
it. Absolutely. As much as Simon wanted
this, believe it or not, it's going to
be better and bigger.
So yeah, for for people who are
interested in how you can use AI dev
tools today, the future of AI native dev
in tooling and practices and programs
and also a third track, a new track that
we've got which is AI tools in action.
So people actually using some of the
best tools around today so that you can
actually get practical hands-on
experience. So yeah, the CFP would be
great event. Yeah. And the CFP is
secretly open. Secretly open. It's open.
We'll share the links in the in the the
show notes. Head over to tesla.io and
you'll be able to find the links from
next week. So you can register to the
event. You can submit your papers as
well. We'd love to we'd love to see you
there again. Yeah, we're really looking
forward to to the event. I think the
whole purpose of the native dev platform
here, right, the community is have
people share their learnings and uh and
I think the conference is like a great
way to get top thinkers around this. you
know whether you're a tool builder,
you're a user of those tools, whether
you are an AI philosopher and you have
some worthy things to share around how
you think it would affect software
development, I think creating a stage
for that so people can share their
learnings is really the purpose of what
we're doing over here. So yeah, would
really looking forward to it and would
love to have you all both attend and
submit your thoughts to present.
Absolutely. And and talking about a
multitude of tools, I had a very
practical session. We'll talk about two
sessions then. on with Farhath who who I
spoke with and then Matty the co-founder
of 11 Labs that you spoke with. So, so
Farhath Razak was I've known him from
the community for a little while now.
Super smart guy. Also really on the
pulse with all the AI AI dev tools
around and there's a number of takeaways
actually from that session, but one of
the biggest takeaways that I had was the
fact that he was actually as a user of
AI dev tools, he doesn't just stick with
one. He uses the right tool at the right
time depending on what he's trying to
get out of it. And in multiple cases, he
actually uses multiple tools. And it's
very interesting how I think there's
probably a number of them that he uses
in premium, a number of them that he
pays for. But that's critical, right?
It's we're not just using a single tool.
We're actually creating a tool belt for
ourselves where we use the right tool at
the right time. This is going to get
into a little bit of buzz word bingo now
as I go through some of these tools.
Yeah. No, but I think I I love the
session. I think very practical. You get
into specifics, but I would say it's a
worth listen if you want to see a
picture of, you know, it's it's an
individual. It's one person. might not
be precisely right for you, but it is a
more complete picture of this is how I
use these tools across many aspects of
my software development work. Yeah.
Yeah. Absolutely. I'll I'll mention a
couple, but then we'll jump on. I think
I think some of the interesting ones
research and ideation moving using
perplexity to understand what texts,
what are the best libraries, what APIs
are there for various projects using
Claude for prototyping, Claude rules to
to adjust to his style for development.
cursor,
clinurf, ruode which gives him the
opportunity to to provide that agentic
workflow uh for web search essentially
there's a number there really is swim
was another one that he he was quite
interested in in in playing with eraser
from a devops point of view and a
deployment point of view there was a ton
do if you're interested in understanding
what each of these tools uh how they can
be used and and and where others use
them that's a must listen yeah I think I
think really good listen to it
Probably the thing that struck me the
most is the cases in which he's actually
using different tools for the same job.
And so he he uses both windsurf and
cursor. So that's if you ask people a
year ago, three years ago to say, "Hey,
which ID do you use?" There would be a
singular answer, right? It was probably
going to be VS Code at the time and
there would be one. How many people were
using multiple ids? Tiny number. And I
think in AI we're seeing more. My bet is
that it's still it's still because this
is all experimentation phase and they
all kind of one up each other in some
specific domain for a brief period of
time and I think in whatever a couple
years time or some period of time people
will get back to I have my tool it's 90%
good at all of these things and it's not
worthwhile for me like not worthy to
switch to another to to use it also I
think they're all benefiting from being
like at least the IDs from being VS code
forks and so they have some familiarity
but still but it is interesting to see
the kind of open-mindedness of of people
to Yeah. No, I loved your session with
Matty. What were your highlights? It's a
really fun conversation with with Matty
from 11 Labs. In case you're not
familiar, 11 Labs is the leader in AI
audio today. So, they're now a $3
billion company. They're they've got
millions of users on is there sort of
the the facto standard today of if you
want to do text to to speech, text to
audio and then you use their their
product. And so, it was really
interesting to hear uh the conversation.
felt privileged a little bit both
because I I know Matic from the sort of
the London scene on it, but also he
doesn't actually do that many sort of
podcast and such. So, it was great to
get a chance to talk about his journey.
It's a little bit less devish, a bit
more about AI entrepreneurship and
building on top of it. But I I think
like a lot of the conversation was fun
and I highly recommend listening to it.
I highlight three takeaways. You know,
one is we talked about the it almost
felt like this sort of textbook story
for how to do an AI startup from a focus
perspective. They started with this big
vision of dubbing which requires a lot
of moving parts from like you're
listening to someone speaking one
language and then you need to understand
and capture that and understand the
voices and who said what when and then
translated and the just a lot of moving
parts. They kind of outlined those and
then they honed in on text to speech as
a specific use case that is that is
valuable in its own right and figured
out sort of good tech innovations to to
break through there and really honed in
on that and voice cloning as the two
kind of core capabilities and and really
succeeded with them. And now they're
expanding back into the the broader sort
of dubbing vision. And they actually
just launched, we recorded it couple
days, a little bit before they launched
uh their speech to text model that gets
gets a bunch of those things right like
the ability to know who said what at
what point and get precise time stamps
and and things like that. And that's
called Scribe, right? And that's called
Scribe. And it's a really cool tool.
Like I tried it out. It's easier to find
use cases off the fly for text to speech
than it is to speech to text. But I
think I really I'm keen to have it in
meetings when there's like multi-person
meetings on it. Yeah. So if there's if
you're today in a Zoom, everybody with
their own computer, it's easy to know
who said what when. But when you're in a
room and multiple people are talking, so
I'm keen to try it out for that. And fun
fact, the room that we are recording in
is called Champagne. And Champagne is an
artist. I believe that's the
Tessellation artist. And all of our
meeting rooms are are called are named
after those who are artists in around
Tessellation. And whenever we're in a
meeting room like this and we're on a
Zoom, I look at the transcript sometimes
and it's basically a conversation
between me and Champagne. And I never
realized my life would get to that at
some stage where I'm just sat talking to
Champagne, but it happens now every now
and then sometimes on the work. So I
think that was really fun to hear the
entrepreneurial story of it. And I think
if you're if you're if you're building
an AI company, you're just reading about
entrepreneurship. I think it was like a
a good sort of textbook again example of
something you would lose. I think the
the second thing that really stayed with
me is the approach to developers and
indeed tackling this problem we we
talked about with the AI labs around
product versus platform. Uh and and so
OpenAI sorry 11 Labs has has always uh
been both a product and uh and kind of
an API for developers. And so they they
you could go to their UI, plop in some
text, pick a voice and and and produce
uh audio without being a developer,
without being any creator. And I think
half their users basically use the
product that way. And then you can use
their APIs to be able to integrate text
to speech into your into your
application. And over time they both
audiences grew, which is interesting.
And they've also in the API have grown
to provide more sort of big building
blocks, conversational agents. And I
found that to be really interesting of
like building building out understanding
the use cases. Again, some of it is just
textbook kind of company building, but
understanding from the use cases people
were using their APIs for what are more
complete programmable use cases they
want to make available and then make
those easy. And so we had a really good
conversation about that. And mostly what
I was trying to push him a bit on is if
you're a developer and you're building
on 11 Labs, how do you like how do you
know to anticipate when would 11 Labs
potentially release a product and and
compete with you? And I I think that is
a question on a lot of sort of AI
startups minds and because they're
building on these AI labs and these AI
labs are a bit declaratively going into
the application layer in certain frauds.
And I liked his answer which really
anchored on transparency. He said here's
our plan. Here's our vision which he
explained more broadly. It talks a
little bit about call centers. It talks
about the dubbing and this world. And he
says if you're in that world, if you're
building if you're using 11 apps to
create dubbing solution on it, you
should anticipate that we will compete
with you and we'll have a product. Uh
but this declaration is also a bit uh uh
stating what they're not planning to do.
So I liked the approach, but also again
I found that conversation to be really
interesting. Yeah, that's the second
bucket there. And from a I don't know if
I'm preempting your third bucket now or
not, but from a organization build point
of view, there are a couple of
interesting things he mentioned. One was
Can I interrupt you over there? The Oh,
absolutely. We had a sort of a scribe
here. Interrupt. We had a fairly
interruptive conversation generally. The
Yeah. Yeah. Sorry, let me let me cut you
off there, guy. Yeah. The Yeah. The
organization conversation was now you're
naturally interrupt.
Yeah. Yeah, the organization because
because a lot of people think okay for
this we need huge amounts of money and
we build a big solid uh very strong team
to to to build this out and the way we
build faster is grow the team but that's
not so much the case in 11 labs right so
so I think in general I think the the
math in these sort of big AI labs is a
little bit different because they spend
buckets of money on on GPUs and all that
sort of training exercise uh but yeah
the organization piece is it was indeed
the sort of my third bullet of it with
on 11 labs
The team is still under 150 people. It
is generally quite small and nibble for
a company that is I think north of 100
million RR and again millions of users
and valued at $3 billion on it. So
that's already quite impressive. But uh
I I tried to probe a little bit Mati's
for Mat's views on long-term research
versus incremental research and asked
him how how do you think about now
investing in breakthrough research
finding out that they have been actually
building a new model versus things that
are just a little bit better and that
was a good conversation I think worth
worth hearing but but then he kept
referring to the teams being small.
Yeah. And someone was like asking how
how small and turns out the team that is
building these sort of big models that
break through next model it's a team of
five people and that's tiny when you
think about the uh impact that each of
these individuals has and even the other
team I think it's some five to 10 people
or seven eight people I think in the the
follow on conversations those people
work on incremental that's also still a
very tiny team serving millions of users
that are using these models and so I
found that to be one interesting two
quite almost like inspiring right to
sort of think about the the breadth of
impact that an individual uh could have
right within those those companies and
and impressive as they build it and and
yeah there was another conversation on
it on um on how do you then run that
organization and a choice that they've
made around uh eliminating titles in
across the organization which I also
found to be I don't know definitely
daring so they've taken away all titles
they didn't really as you probe in they
do have you are the team lead but it's a
bit like what you might tell your a good
parenting philosophy is when you talk to
your kids, don't tell them that they are
stupid. Tell them they've done something
stupid, right? Like or don't tell them
they are smart, they tell they've done
something smart. So they get to develop
a little bit their identity, but they
judge their actions by their actions,
not just embed all of that to I will
always do that. And so it's a little bit
like that. They said you are managing
this team versus you are the manager of
this team. Uh so they have functional
kind of a semi-titles.
Uh but they've they've chosen like to to
really embrace that sort of companywide
to not have seniority reflected in the
title which it's quite a different vibe.
It's quite a different vibe to us at
Tesla, isn't it? Because it's just you
who we give like a low for they've never
worked for Guy, he always insists never
look him in the eyes and of course your
royal highness sometimes is also
and of course if you're referring to him
it's always grandmaster Pjani for yeah
it's quite it must be interesting to to
work in that. It was it was it was kind
of a a fun conversation. Clearly Tesla
we also talk about head of insight
trying to support avoid the sort of
whatever CXO type titles be nimble. It's
interesting to think about how that that
scales and how whether that works better
when you're a more resourcecentric
organization versus product. Yeah, that
is. So I think really fun conversation
on it. Highly recommend that you listen
to it uh and that you try out 11 Labs.
Frankly, like it's it's a fun product.
But these are probably my three big
takeaways. Amazing. Amazing. We're
wrapping up here now, guys. Yeah, really
fun conversations. I I I definitely
think you should listen back to those
last couple for sure. Yeah, we've got
some fun coming up next month as well. I
I teased the Macy session which is
coming out next week. Of course, if you
don't want to miss a an episode, make
sure you subscribe. We have almost at
10,000 subscribers across across our
platforms. So, yeah, help us grow that,
which is great for a small also not a
small a an early stage podcast. Yeah,
absolutely. So help us grow that. And
and yeah, of course, finally the AI
native Dev Con. Feel free to feel free
to respond to the CFP and make sure you
register for that. But till next time,
GIO, it's been a pleasure. It has been.
Yeah. And I hope you join us for the
next one. Tune in soon.
[Music]
Thanks for tuning in. Join us next time
on the AI Native Dev brought to you by
Tesla.